Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
They idolize the messenger, Jesus. This is
why he disowns them in Matthew 7:23.
They will go to him on the Day of Judgment and say "Lord, Lord, did we not prophesy in your name? Did we not perform miracles in your name?"
And he will say "out of my sight, I don't
know you, get out of here."
This is what Jesus will tell the Christians.
And God looked down on the planet Earth and
He saw you and me committing idolatry in our Contact Prayer.
As we're making Salat Prayer, we will say, "Muhammad, Ale (family of) Muhammad, Ibrahim, Ale (family of) Ibrahim."
When God tells us in the Quran, very clearly,
a commandment in 72:18, وَأَنَّ الْمَسَاجِدَ
(72:18) وَأَنَّ ٱلْمَسَـٰجِدَ لِلَّهِ فَلَا تَدْعُوا۟ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ أَحَدًۭا
The mosque, the places of worship, the acts of worship
belong to God. Do not mention anyone else.
لَا تَدْعُوا۟ مَعَ ٱللَّهِ أَحَدًۭا
No one with God.
Certainly, Muhammad is someone and Ibrahim
is someone.
And you and I were doing this for many years.
God looked down on the planet Earth and He
saw the Muslims not doing the Zakat charity.
They're all, they are doing it wrong. We were doing it wrong. You and I were doing it wrong.
God told us in a very clear message that you
must give out the charity, the Zakat, the day of harvest.
The day you harvest, Sura 6, verse 141.
And what were we doing? We were giving the Zakat once a year,
2.5 percent of our savings above
a certain limit.
And this is what all the Muslims are doing.
The Zakat and Salat are mentioned together.
And God wanted us to get out the Zakat to
our parents, then our relatives.
If they are rich, then to the orphans.
There is a specific system in the Quran.
And this must be done according to Quran, the day
you receive income.
We do not harvest fruit. We harvest paychecks.
So, God wanted us to do the Salat, the Contact
Prayer correctly.
He wanted us to do the Zakat correctly.
He wanted us to Fast correctly.
The ablution is wrong that we used to do. You and I, God looked down and He saw that you and I were doing the ablution wrong.
8 or 9 steps when He gave us 4 steps.
God saw that everything we're doing was
wrong.
God looked down and He saw us associating the name of Muhammad with the name of God in the first pillar of Islam, the Shahada.
And this is why this prayer of thanks.
Because if someone walks through this door and said "La Elaha Ella Allah." There is no god except the One True God, we will be very happy.
You do the same thing at the Islamic centers
or at any mosque in the Middle East, in Egypt or Karachi or Iran.
Go walk in the door and say "La Elaha Ella Allah", and they go like this.
"Where is the rest?"
Now, if you don't come up with the rest, they
will literally beat you up.
The great criterion, it's in the Quran, Sura 39,
verse 45.
When God alone is mentioned, the hearts of
the disbelievers shrink with aversion.
This is why we thank God.
Because He looked down and He saw that you
and me were doing it wrong.
We were committing idolatry, the only unforgivable
offense.
God wanted us to know that we are the creatures
who agreed with Satan.
Long time ago, a few billion years ago, Satan
violated the absolute kingship of God.
He thought in his head that God can have
another god besides Him.
Satan initiated that idea.
And there are some who said "yeah, Satan can
do that, he's powerful, he's got the qualifications, he can do that."
Some creatures did agree with Satan.
You know who those creatures are?
That's you and me.
God wanted us to know that.
And God calls Himself Arrahman Arraheem.
The Most Gracious, Most Merciful, Merciful beyond belief, our belief.
So, God told Satan "you go, you're doomed"
because he still thinks that he can be a god besides God.
But the creatures, you and I, who agreed with
Satan mentally, are given a second chance. This is it.
God is giving us a second chance.
And God wanted us to know that.
God's kingdom, where all constituents of God
know that God is
the Absolute Lord and Master, the kingdom
is going from eternity to eternity.
And in Sura 38, we see a dispute happening. Sura 38.
(38:69) مَا كَانَ لِىَ مِنْ عِلْمٍۭ بِٱلْمَلَإِ ٱلْأَعْلَىٰٓ إِذْ يَخْتَصِمُونَ
Feud, Dispute, in the High Society.
Satan initiated an idea.
And we agreed with him.
So, God put us all in Adam,
and isolated us from that dimension.
We don't remember those things, because we
are given a second chance to take back this idea
that, that "Satan, maybe, he can do it. Maybe, God alone is not enough, maybe." This is why
associating anything with God
is not forgivable.
This is why we are thanking God for being
born at this time when God willed that we remove all associations.
That we say "La Elaha Ella Allah" and we are
happy with it. This is the criterion.
You go in any mosque in the world and say "La Elaha Ella Allah", they will beat you up.
In fact, they come in our mosque and we tell them "La Elaha Ella Allah", and they want to beat us up.
Now, listen to this, because you can tell them
that.
Tell them "you do not want, you do not want Allah if Muhammad
is not with him." And this is the truth.
When you say "La Elaha Ella Allah" alone, try
it.
Go to any mosque, any Islamic center, anywhere
in the world, and say "La Elaha Ella Allah",
they don't want Allah without Muhammad.
I have recordings of songs from Egypt and
other places that enrage Ismail,
where God is a messenger of Muhammad.
They pray, they pray to God to go to Muhammad
and get his intercession, get Shefa'a for them.
Dr. Khalifa: I have it in the mosque, you can hear it.
Ismail Barakat: This is the official, Din of, religious radio of Egypt.
Dr. Khalifa: God looked down at the planet earth and He
saw that His message, the Quran, has been tampered with.
They added, they added two verses in praise of the prophet. What else?
At the end of Sura 9. And God wanted to remove those two verses.
God wanted the Quran to be pure, restored.
And God wanted us to know when will the world
end.
It is in the Quran, and God wants to reveal
it now to our generation.
And we thank God for being that generation.
God wanted to reveal the miracle of the Quran, an overwhelming miracle.
And God wanted to tell us that our only source
must be His word, the Quran.
And He did it mathematically.
I'm gonna share this with you, which will
demonstrate the miracle and why the Quran alone.
The word alone is mentioned in the Quran 6
times.
It's a very limited number of mentioning.
The word "alone", "Wahdahu" in Arabic, is mentioned
only 6 times.
5 times are referring to God "Allah Wahdahu."
And one time is referring to the Quran, Al-Quran
Wahdahu, the Quran alone. Ok?
You look at any translation or Tafsir of
Quran, and they never say "Al-Quran Wahdahu."
They tell you that this "Wahdahu, alone" refers
to Rabbaka, to your Lord, to God, not to the Quran.
Because it's a doctrine from God.
It says "you follow the Quran alone", and they
don't wanna do that. So, they distorted it.
Now, listen to the mathematics that God put
in the Quran.
If you take the Sura and the verses where
the word alone is mentioned, the total is 19 x 19, 361.
This is, these are the 5 "alone" that refer to God.
If you take the one referring to the Quran,
this destroys the, the criterion.
It is, it is not a multiple of 19 anymore.
And this proves that alone in Sura 17 refers
to the Quran alone.
Linguistically, linguistically, it
is referring to the Quran. It came after the Quran.
It says "when you preach about God in the Quran
alone, they turn away in aversion." They run away in aversion.
Now, God could have said "when you preach God alone in the Quran, they run away in aversion", but He didn't do it that way.
He put the word "alone" after "the Quran", and
this is supported, as you see, mathematically.
So, God wanted to establish this fact, that religious teachings must come from the Quran and the Quran alone, nothing else.
God wanted us to believe that He is doing
everything.
Now, this is very difficult concept, but
we find it in Sura 8, verse 17. 817 is a multiple of 19.
And it says "it is not you who threw when
you threw, it is God who threw."
The Quran, in about 100 verses, tells us "people who believe that He is the Lord of the universe, the Lord of the great throne, these people are going to Hell."
Why?
Because they do not believe that God is doing
everything.
This doctrine that God wants us to know, sheds
a whole new light on the concept of submission.
Because if you know that God is doing everything,
you will not object. You will never be unhappy.
You'll not object to anything. You will be a Muslim.
You will be a submitter. This is what word "Muslim" is.
God wanted us to know that Muhammad wrote
the Quran with his hand,
that he was not an illiterate man. A ridiculous concept.
They were looking for a miracle in the Quran,
the wrong way.
And they thought "if we say that Muhammad is illiterate, he cannot read or write, this would make him a fantastic miracle.
So, they lie about their idol.
He wrote the Quran with his hand, we have
the proof, and God wanted us to know that.
God wanted to, God wants us to know that the Masjid Al-Aqsa,
the Aqsa mosque is not in Jerusalem.
It is in the seventh heaven, in the seventh
universe,
and wants us to know that Muhammad went
there and received the Quran over there.
And God wanted us to know the secret of perfect
happiness.
We're gonna go into all details for all
of these.
On page 69 of Rabbi Kushner, Kushner's book,
he said "I don't know why people are mortal and fated to die.
"And I don't know why people die at the time
and in the way they do."
Perhaps you can try to understand it by picturing
what the world would be like if people lived forever.
Of course, God can do that if He so willed.
But we know the reason why we came to this
world and why the human being dies.
But for all these reasons, God tells us in
the Quran that after all the prophets have come,
in Sura 3, verse 81, God will send
a messenger who will confirm all the prophets
and restore all their messages to their pristine
purity.
Now, do we believe the Quran? Do we believe in the Quran?
If we believe in the Quran, we will believe
this verse, 81 in Sura 3.
And as most of you are aware, that some, some person
in South Africa wrote an article saying that
the messenger who will come and confirm all
the prophets is Muhammad.
This person fell in his, in the trap of his ignorance,
because in Sura 33, God says that it is not Muhammad.
That Muhammad was one of the prophets who
made the covenant and the pledge with God
to believe and support and help the messenger
who will come after all the prophets.
So, if we believe that verse, we have to ask
ourselves "who is this messenger? What does he look like?"
How about Ronald Reagan?
I mean, we have to be open-minded.
I mean, just imagine, how about your uncle?
Think of your uncle, think of the brother
of your father, for example.
Is he good? Could he be? See, we have to be open-minded.
Because, as Parivash read the verses that says "they swore solemnly by God that if a warner came to them, they will be better guided, they will treat him better."
Then, when the warner came, this increased
their aversion because of their arrogance.
Because the human nature, when you say "this
human being is God's messenger",
the human nature, unless we overcome the ego, will be
averse to that idea.
But we must be open to that.
I mean, we just have to ask the person "what is
your proof?"
The Quran says that. The Quran says,
(2:111) هَاتُوا۟ بُرْهَـٰنَكُمْ
Bring your
proof.
So, I'm going to close with this, that we
must be open to the idea that God told us in the Quran.
It is very clear, and there are many, many
places in the Quran that will explain it and make it very clear to us.
I want to introduce all of you to each other.
And would you carry the camera on your shoulder, (unintelligible)? Just...
We're gonna start with Raymond, the one
and only.
Take the camera itself easily, unless it's easier
for you. Alright.
Raymond comes from Vancouver. He's one of
the original strivers, and, with the very first
Dr. Khalifa: fights where they sent warriors from Saudi
Arabia to come and combat us.
Raymond: Salãmun ‘Alaykum
Dr. Khalifa: Vancouver, BC. Next to him is Ahmad Baruni.
He's very shy. We love him very much.
He is, without him we cannot make a ton of (unintelligible)
No, it's alright.
No, no, you can see him.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay, wave your hand.
Ismail Barakat: Ahmad Baruni, stand up.
Dr. Khalifa: Hamid.
Ismail Barakat: Everybody knows him.
Dr. Khalifa: My brother-in-law, Ahmad Rayan, Mã Shã Allãh,
very strong believer.
Dr. Khalifa: Brother Abdul Muta'al came all the way from
New York.
Abdul Muta'al: Salãmun ‘Alaykum.
Audience: ‘Alaykum Al-Salam.
Dr. Khalifa: And brother Ezeddin came with his sister-in-law,
Naima Turner.
He is testing the water. He wants to find
out what the truth is.
And his tribes come all the way from California.
Brother Mahmoud Mo'ini, he's, he's, God bless him, he's a strong member of Masjid Tucson.
Farhad Mo'ini: Farhad
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm?
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, Farhad Mo'ini, excuse me.
Dr. Khalifa: Farhad Mo'ini.
Brother Hussein Kawsa'i, I discouraged him,
but he came, despite all the discouragement. This is what God...
Dr. Khalifa: ....(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: At 1:30, I'm supposed to give thanks to God
and congratulations to you.
And I think this will be my chance to, so that you can finish early, there are some people who are trying to catch planes.
So, I expect, IN SHAA ALLAH, to just have lunch, eat
and run.
Dr. Khalifa: After we have lunch, we'll just leave.
A woman: Do it 2 times.
Ismail Barakat: No, no, let's do...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Hmm?
A woman: Do it 2 times. That was 2 times.
Ismail Barakat: Let's do it before we run out of time.
Well, let's start with congratulating you because
Allah Subhanahu Wa Ta'ala saw us heading for a conference.
Absolutely, the greatest collection of people
who worship God alone and uphold the word of God alone.
There is no question that this is a very special
spot in the universe.
And you will agree with me that there are
angels that are full of excitement roaming around us here.
And also, I, I have to go to the book of Job and
quote a few examples from there.
Where Satan told God "why shouldn't Job worship
You?"
He is happy, he's content, everything is
going right for him.
If I touch his properties, he blasphemes against You.
And God told Satan "okay, you can go and touch
his properties, but you cannot touch him."
God puts limits on Satan.
So, Satan went and destroyed all of Job's properties.
And Job continued to worship God alone.
Dr. Khalifa: It didn't make any difference. And you know the rest of the story.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And I fixed this.
A woman: Wait, wait, wait. I got it.
Dr. Khalifa: These people are not strong.
If you give them just a little bit of trouble,
they will turn around and go back.
And God told Satan "okay, you can have them within limits. Give them some confusion and some overheating cars, and, and let them get lost."
Dr. Khalifa: ... (unintelligible) recite it this way or not? (unintelligible)
The way Parivash, this beautiful recitation
of the Quran.
We had, we, we had a discussion with the, the Azhar seems
to be, like I called it before, a castle of, of Satan.
And we had the rest of Al-Azhar fail before
our eyes, but anyway, we had a discussion with him.
And he disagreed with the way the Quran is
recited by Parivash, for example, or the other reciters.
(unintelligible) the demonstration, the way he wants
the Quran to be recited, it's a very repulsive, ugly recitation.
And, and in his opinion, he thinks...
(unintelligible). Thank you.
He thinks that the Quran
should be recited in that way.
And, so, anyway, we had a big discussion.
And somebody asked the extreme question "how
about adding music to the Quran?"
I mean, what's wrong with anything that will make us listen to the Quran, and learn the Quran, and understand the Word of God?
That was said jokingly.
And then, the very first morning after that,
and we were guests at my brother's house,
where he has some beautiful flowers, the
landscaping outside, so Kat wanted to take
some pictures of the flowers with the video,
to use as background for, for our video programs.
And it just happened that Parivash was passing by, and Kat said "why don't I have you recite some Quran while I'm shooting the flowers?"
And Parivash came and started reciting in the most beautiful, heavenly recitation that you can hear, for example,
at the beginning of the videotape, called "The Great Debate." Some of you did hear it.
Parivash started to read the Quran, and
sure enough, a bird came and provided, God provided music.
Whenever Parivash read the Quran, the bird
read the Quran with her.
It was just beautiful harmony, and an absolute
miracle.
One of the things that we witnessed.
Okay, maybe that was a coincidence.
Outside right now, brother Abdul Muta'al from New York, he wants, wants to take his collecting mementos of the conference,
souvenirs, to take back to New York.
And Parivash happened to be passing by as
he was holding his recorder, right?
So, he asked Parivash "would you please come and
recite some Quran for my record?"
Dr. Khalifa: You know something?
Dr. Khalifa: A bird.
A man: A bird.
Dr. Khalifa: Did you hear any birds this morning? No.
A bird showed up, started singing along
with Parivash.
And it is not...
It is not as, as pronounced or profound like the videotape that you're going to see something. But here is the evidence, folks.
Notice, notice the bird. It is not as pronounced as the other one,
but it is there.
And it's a confirmation, absolute confirmation
of that.
Parivash: This is Parivash. Salãmun ‘Alaykum to everybody.
I'm very glad that I'm here for convention.
Congratulations to all of you who, Alhamdu Lillah,
worship Allah and follow Quran alone.
And really congratulations for being, IN SHAA ALLAH,
all united together, Alhamdu Lillah.
Now, one verse is in the Quran,
رَبَّنَا لَا تُزِغْ قُلُوبَنَا بَعْدَ إِذْ هَدَيْتَنَا وَهَبْ لَنَا مِن لَّدُنكَ رَحْمَةً
(3:8) إِنَّكَ أَنتَ ٱلْوَهَّابُ
That means, our Lord, let not our hearts falter after being guided by You. And shower us with Your mercy. You are the Grantor.
We are very happy, yes, because we worship
God alone.
And we are really really a very lucky generation.
Parivash: God bless you all, IN SHAA ALLAH. God bless.
Abdul Muta'al: This young lady has a sprouting voice, I tell
you. I'm trying to get some of it on tape so that you can hear it.
Parivash: Ok.
Parivash: Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem. Now or later?
Abdul Muta'al: Now.
Parivash: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Well, (unintelligible)
Audience: (unintelligible)
A woman: This is wild.
Parivash: (unintelligible) Alhamdu Lillah.
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
Parivash: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: What did you say?
Parivash: Yeah, after (unintelligible)
Edip: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, okay. I, I heard it, I heard it.
Parivash: (unintelligible)
A man: (unintelligible)
A woman: (unintelligible)
Edip: didn't know (unintelligible)
Parivash:
وَقُل رَّبِّ أَدْخِلْنِى مُدْخَلَ صِدْقٍۢ وَأَخْرِجْنِى مُخْرَجَ صِدْقٍۢ
(17:80) وَٱجْعَل لِّى مِن لَّدُنكَ سُلْطَـٰنًۭا نَّصِيرًۭا
Dr. Khalifa: Where did the bird come from?
Parivash: (unintelligible)
Parivash: Subhan Allah.
A woman: Subhan Allah.
Parivash: There's more after this.
Dr. Khalifa: There's more?
Parivash: Yes.
Parivash:
وَأَخْرِجْنِى مُخْرَجَ صِدْقٍۢ
(17:80) وَٱجْعَل لِّى مِن لَّدُنكَ سُلْطَـٰنًۭا نَّصِيرًۭا
(17:81) وَقُلْ جَآءَ ٱلْحَقُّ وَزَهَقَ ٱلْبَـٰطِلُ ۚ إِنَّ ٱلْبَـٰطِلَ كَانَ زَهُوقًۭا
Parivash: Subhan Allah. (unintelligible)
Parivash: (unintelligible) Alhamdu Lillah
Parivash: See?
Abdul Muta'al: Alhamdu Lillah.
Abdul Muta'al: (unintelligible)
Parivash:
(17:81) وَقُلْ جَآءَ ٱلْحَقُّ وَزَهَقَ ٱلْبَـٰطِلُ ۚ إِنَّ ٱلْبَـٰطِلَ كَانَ زَهُوقًۭا
Parivash: Again?
Dr. Khalifa: By the way, this verse says "the truth has
come and falsehood has vanished." Alhamdu Lillah
Dr. Khalifa:
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
Quran Is Wisdom
Just the subtitle provokes a short discussion
here because people who are trying very hard to go to Hell,
people who are storming the
gates of Hell and digging tunnels under the fence to go to Hell.
They say that Quran is the
scripture and Hadith is the wisdom.
Because God says in Quran consistently...
scripture and wisdom.
And God says this to every prophet, Jesus,
Moses, Muhammad.
But of course, they lose sight of this.
In this verse 39, we are told that
Quran is wisdom. When you acquire Quran, you acquire wisdom.
Before, verses before this one are giving us a list
of commandments, which are, include the ten commandments.
You shall not kill. You shall honor our parents.
Of course, the first commandment, you shall
worship God alone.
And then now comes verse 39 which says,
[17:39]  This is some of the wisdom inspired to you by your Lord. You shall not set up another god beside GOD, lest you end up in Gehenna, blamed and defeated.
So, it, if you can make a mental picture in your mind when you, when these people tell you that the Hadith is the wisdom, remember this 17:39.
Cause 17:39 is a clear statement that Quran is the
wisdom.
Verse 40 says,
[17:40]  Has your Lord given you boys, while giving Himself the angels as daughters?! How could you utter such a blasphemy?
[17:41]  We have cited in this Quran (all kinds of examples), that they may take heed. But it only augments their aversion.
There is a tendency among, among especially the Arabs of those days and even now, and some other nationalities, a prejudice to baby boys.
Before the baby is born, they want a boy.
This is their wish.
But at the risk of being prejudiced against
boys, I say girls are better than boys.
Just to counter that, to counter that general erroneous bigoted
trend.
But it seems like when we have sons and daughters,
when the sons get married, we lose them.
But when the daughters get married, we gain
a son-in-law.
This seems to be a general, general trend.
So, to, to correct the biased statement just made, I say when the boys make it and become believers, they are wonderful.
But the girls have, definitely have an advantage as far as God is concerned in that God created the man with more ego.
And this is a real problem.
I mean, if it's, this is why when the boys, when we have boys and they are believers, they are wonderful.
When we have girls and they are believers,
they are fantastic.
So, this bigoted principle is, is very wrong, of
course.
The Quran condemns it in the strongest terms.
In Sura 16, for example, the Sura before
this one, as to how they react to a baby boy or a baby girl.
The Quran condemns their, their prejudice.
[17:41]  We have cited in this Quran (all kinds of examples), that they may take heed. But it only augments their aversion.
[17:42]  Say, "If there were other gods beside Him, as they claim, they would have tried to overthrow the Possessor of the throne."
So, God is discussing it in, in logical terms.
If we had 3 gods, they will overthrow
each other until one of them dominates.
Saeed, why are you hiding?
Dr. Khalifa: Come back here. Do you have a Quran?
Saeed: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, you come here and be cozy.
We want to see you.
Dr. Khalifa: For exhibiting (unintelligible). Get a copy of the Quran, my friend.
Saeed: We'll get a picture, too?
Dr. Khalifa: Why not?
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Yeah, open page 286.
Verse 43 says,
[17:43]  Be He glorified, He is much too exalted, far above their utterances.
Their utterances cause mountains to shatter.
Because, I mean, it's, it's like putting a virus
next to you.
Well, of course, it's much more than that. So, the proportion is much more than that.
When they say that a virus is your partner
in this business, for example.
The vice president for the Islamic University in
Medina tells us "you have only God there? Is that all?" on the wall.
He wants Muhammad next to God.
"Is that all?" Can you imagine? I mean, it made me cringe.
That was the end of the conversation.
Really, it makes you cringe. He said "Is that all?" I mean, he's talking about God. He said "Is that all?"
This is why verse 43 says,
[17:43]  Be He glorified, He is much too exalted, far above their utterances.
I mean, you and I are gonna meet this man
on the Day of Judgment.
Let's see how he can repeat that question. "Is that all?" he says.
[17:44]  Glorifying Him are the seven universes, the earth, and everyone in them. There is nothing that does not glorify Him, but you do not comprehend their glorification. He is Clement, Forgiver.
Even the disbelievers glorify God, unwillingly.
Because their heart beats, they cannot change
the number of their heartbeats.
By the way their intestines, their peristalsis
works, they cannot control any of that, their bodies.
[17:44]  Glorifying Him are the seven universes, the earth, and everyone in them. There is nothing that does not glorify Him, but you do not comprehend their glorification. He is Clement, Forgiver.
We went through the fact that this wall glorifies
God, the carpet, this tape recorder.
Because every atom has molecules and has nuclei
and electrons and neutrons, protons, and they're
all moving in precise orbits according
to God's law. This is how they glorify God.
They never deviate, never.
Otherwise, all of a sudden, this book will
become gold or something, or lead.
You know, I mean, Don't say "I wish it is", or something. Because it can turn to lead.
And it takes minor changes in the electrons,
the numbers in the orbits of the electrons.
Dr. Khalifa: There is nothing that does not glorify God.
A man: (unintelligible)
A man: Oh, it is gold.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The invisible barrier.
The invisible barrier explains your experiences when you're talking to the people, giving them very strong proof, and they don't move.
It doesn't reach them.
[17:45]  When you read the Quran, we place between you and those who do not believe in the Hereafter an invisible barrier.
This is one of three important criteria that
tell us, that tell us whether we believe in the Hereafter or not.
You and I claim to believe in the Hereafter,
but that doesn't mean a thing.
When we claim with our mouth that we believe in the Hereafter, it doesn't mean a thing. You have to pass these three criteria.
This is one of them.
[17:45]  When you read the Quran, we place between you and those who do not believe in the Hereafter an invisible barrier.
[17:46]  And we place shields around their minds, to prevent them from understanding the Quran, and deafness in their ears. And when you preach your Lord, using the Quran alone,* they run away in aversion.
So, there's the criterion.
If you tell them Quran alone, and they are
averse to this idea, this means they do not believe in the Hereafter.
No matter what they say with their mouth.
The other criteria is the same number of verse,
45, but in Sura 39. You wanna look at it, Sura 39.
It's a very simple criteria that we can apply
to ourselves and to the people we talk to.
Page 463, verse 45, I called it "The Greatest Criterion."
It says,
[39:45]  When GOD ALONE is mentioned, the hearts of those who do not believe in the Hereafter shrink with aversion. But when others are mentioned beside Him, they rejoice.*
Yusuf Ali, outright, refused to translate this
verse correctly.
He refused to use the word "alone", which he
translated correctly in other places in the Quran.
But when it came to "when God alone is mentioned,
they become averse", he became averse.
And he, he made, he changed "alone" to "the one and only",
which doesn't mean anything. It doesn't mean "alone."
Because "the One and only" means "the Great,
the Gracious, Merciful, the One and only."
But "alone" is a very specific word.
And Yusuf Ali refused to... you can see the
other translations squirm around it and try to avoid saying, saying it.
Because they apply the criterion to themselves
and they cannot, they don't pass.
It proves that they do not believe in the
Hereafter, which is a, a prerequisite for going to Heaven.
So, this is a criterion. When you talk to someone
and you tell them "God alone", or you just talk about God alone,
and they tell you "you're
a Kafir", which is a very funny statement.
You tell them "La Elaha Ella Allah" and they say "you're a Kafir." What!?
I mean, I'm saying "worship God alone", you tell me, you call me I'm a Kafir because I say "God alone"?
Ehsan always answers them, says
کفرنا بِشِرْكِكُمْ
She says "Yes, I am a Kafir of your Shirk" or idolatry.
Which is a statement in Sura 60.
It's a very funny statement when you tell
them "worship God alone", they say "you're a Kafir."
Dr. Khalifa: Kafir of, Kafir of what?
Na'ima: I mean the, I mean the, the people that we know, I mean, we used to know,
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Na'ima: they said "these people, they are against Muhammad."
Na'ima: I said "why don't you say the other one,
why don't you say "these people worship God alone?"
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Na'ima: I mean, they told me one time, actually, one
time only "do you still worship God alone?"
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Did they hear what you were saying?
Dr. Khalifa: Muwaheddin (monotheists), yes.
Na'ima: Muwaheddin (monotheists)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Na'ima (Speaking Arabic): (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I'm gonna... Na'ima, Ehsan developed a very good idea, it's gonna help you when you, when you argue with those flopsters.
She was arguing with an Egyptian fellow in
Canada.
And she told them that when you say "La Elaha Ella Allah, Muhammad Rasulallah", among the commandments you break is
the commandment of making distinction
among the messengers.
You shall not make distinction among the
messengers.
So, she asked him "when was the last time you
said "La Elaha Ella Allah, Saleh Rasulallah?"
He said "just because I don't say "Saleh Rasulallah"
doesn't mean I don't believe he's Rasulallah."
Dr. Khalifa: She said "exactly, just because we don't say "Muhammad Rasulallah" doesn't mean we don't believe that Muhammad is Rasulallah."
A woman: Wow.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. I mean, he just fell in the trap very nicely.
Yes, we have it, we have the conversation recorded.
There are a few other ideas that will come.
So, here now, we saw two criteria. Criteria.
The one in verse 45 of Sura 17, 45-46, which
says "Quran alone."
When you say "the Quran alone" and they become
averse to it, this tells them and tells you,
and we'll bear witness on them on the Day of Judgment that they did not believe in the Hereafter.
If somebody tells me "Quran alone" and I don't
like it, this tells me
that I don't believe in the Hereafter, even if I'm saying it with
my mouth. I can swear by God that I believe in the Hereafter.
But if I'm not content with the Quran alone,
I'm a liar.
This is a criterion.
Now, the other, the third criterion is in 6:113.
And this is in page 142.
You start at 112, it says "Hadith & Sunna: Fabrications by the Prophet's Enemies"
and accepting them again is a criterion for disbelief
in Hereafter.
Because 112 says "we also set up enemies against
every prophet", and this of course includes the prophet Muhammad.
[6:112]  ...—human and jinn devils—who inspire in each other fancy words, ...
Another description of Hadith.
[6:112]  ... in order to deceive. Had your Lord willed, they would not have done it. You shall disregard them and their fabrications.
So, why did God will that they fabricate those
things?
In 113, it says
[6:113]  This is to let the minds of those who do not believe in the Hereafter...
OK. This is the common denominator
here. Disbelief in the Hereafter.
[6:113]  ... listen to such fabrications, and accept them, and thus expose their real convictions.*
Because with their mouth they say "we believe
in the Hereafter."
But if they accept any source besides the
Quran as their source for religious guidance,
this is the criterion that tells me, tells
them, that they do not believe in the Hereafter.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the first two criteria are really the same thing, but in two different ways. One of them "if you accept a source other than the Quran, you don't ..."
Dr. Khalifa: ... souls and their families on the Day of Resurrection.
Most certainly, this is the worst loss.
Losing the soul is, is literal.
When we don't pray, we don't worship
God alone, the soul shrinks.
Not only to zero, it goes to negative.
It'll just be full of negative charges.
Losing their souls and their families, because
a soul that is shrunk is repulsed by everything else.
Do you remember those movies about gambling
in the Old West, and drinking, and shooting and killing?
Murders, fighting, shooting, and killing are
always associated with the places of gambling and, and drinking.
Because the souls are so shrunk, there is
so much hate.
Yeah, it's amazing how they show those movies,
and they have poker hands or something,
Dr. Khalifa: and they focus on the faces, there's so much
hatred and cheating, money grabbing,
A woman: greed
Dr. Khalifa: Greed, and then they shoot each other.
Dr. Khalifa: They're reaching for their guns, you know, every few
minutes.
A man: They have, they have their guns on their lap, actually.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Exactly.
A man: They have their tokens all on the table, and a whiskey.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Gambling and drinking.
A man: In France, for instance, they show these films,
all the films they show in one week in France.
A man: There are so many killings and, and murders, and
it's only this.
Dr. Khalifa: That was murder week or something?
A man: No, it's any week.
Dr. Khalifa: The whole week
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, every week.
A man: Yeah, and it's not about that.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. It affects the people.
A man: Of course.
[39:16]  They will have masses of fire on top of them, and under them. GOD thus alerts His servants: O My servants, you shall reverence Me.
[39:17]  As for those who discarded the worship of all idols, and devoted themselves totally to GOD, they have the good news. Give good news to My servants.
[39:18]  They are the ones who examine all words, then follow the best. These are the ones whom GOD has guided; these are the ones who possess intelligence.
[39:19]  For those who have incurred the retribution, can you save those who are already in Hell?
[39:20]  As for those who reverence their Lord, they will have mansions upon mansions constructed for them, with flowing streams. This is GOD's promise, and GOD never breaks His promise.
[39:21]  Do you not see that GOD sends down from the sky water, then places it into underground wells, then produces with it plants of various colors, then they grow until they turn yellow, and become hay? This should be a reminder for those who possess intelligence.
Dr. Khalifa: I think I'll stop here, have general discussions
if there's any.
A man: By interruption here by Makan, is there
any devil, Sheytan has any action here or any...?
A man: For example, Makan, but because I dropped, it makes me a little nervous (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Say it again. Start all over again.
A man: Ok.
A man: Makan, but because it makes me nervous,
my son, Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: Uh huh.
A man: So, he interrupts, really, and makes me nervous,
I can't understand.
Dr. Khalifa: So, Muhammad is making noise?
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: That's natural.
A man: Does Sheytan has any, Sheytan has any...?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: Power?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. Yes, he scares you and makes you nervous.
You need to relax.
Concentrate on that.
Dr. Khalifa: Don't worry, he's in God's hand.
A man: Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa (Speaking Arabic): (unintelligible). Yes. Yes.
A woman: Does the jinn that you are born with know (unintelligible)
A woman: as a early child, can he already start when we are too young to really understand and (unintelligible) the Quran?
A woman: (unintelligible) the influence (unintelligible) not like (unintelligible) but stuff like "there's no God" and already start...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, that will be, that'll be from Satan because it has to do with God.
Dr. Khalifa: But remember that the jinn is also a baby
at the time you're a baby.
A woman: Oh.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Our, our qualities as, as humans are not really completely... We grow in our human qualities, and so does
the jinn.
Dr. Khalifa: He also grows in his jinn qualities.
A man: So, this, this childishness in children is what the
jinn is controlling?
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, I didn't say that. I said the exact opposite.
Dr. Khalifa: I said, when they're children, the
jinn is also children.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm not...
Dr. Khalifa: It's not an adult jinn getting hold of a child.
A man: No, I heard that.
Dr. Khalifa: Jinn also is a child.
A man: Yeah, but I mean the age. So,...
A woman: It's directly proportionate.
Dr. Khalifa: You mean to the age? Yes.
As soon as the human being begins to reason,
so will the jinn.
And he will, for example, he will tell you, as of now
"don't get up early in the morning to do the Morning Prayer."
"It's more fun to sleep" he'll tell you.
He'll even keep you from school homework.
He'll make it boring for you.
You know, it's really crazy. The jinn tells us the things that are bad
for us.
I mean, Don't they realize that if I starve, he'll starve
too?
You know.
Dr. Khalifa: Because they share in our pain and our joys.
A woman: In other words, there are as many jinns as
human beings?
A woman: No.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes. No, as many companions as human beings. Every human being is two.
A human being and a companion. A human being and a companion.
Dr. Khalifa: Now, jinns are the freed companions.
A man: But Satan was...
Dr. Khalifa: There are many more of those.
A man: But Satan must be really stupid because he
wants to prove that he's competent.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: But basically, he's just proving the opposite
all the time, willingly.
Dr. Khalifa: How?
A man: Well, by, I mean, he should be as smart to
see that his ways are destructive, that they don't lead anywhere.
A man: So, why can't he, he, he have enough intelligence and
draw the conclusions then?
Dr. Khalifa: give up.
Dr. Khalifa: Because he's still hoping that he can fix
everything. Yeah.
A man: Yes, like...
Dr. Khalifa: He's still hoping. Yeah.
A man: Just like the Perestroika.
A man: He, he has to continue the Perestroika.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: That's right. Yes. Very good, very good analogy.
A man: So, Rashad, just to, to understand a little bit what he was saying, IN SHAA ALLAH, right now, it is just 10% of the population.
A man: If I understood right at the time you said
"the earth is populated just 10% of the global..."
Dr. Khalifa: The total human population, yes.
A man: So, he thinks he still has lots of time to
catch up.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, he's still, he's still hoping that he will fix everything.
Dr. Khalifa: But things keep popping up.
A man: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Just as he takes care of polio, for example,
AIDS comes up.
I mean, he's working on AIDS and so on. So,...
It's, it's like somebody who's guarding a wall or
a dam that has leaks in it.
I always give this analogy.
And he puts his finger in the hole to stop
the water, but another leak comes up, he puts in other hole.
Dr. Khalifa: It seems like right now he's got all 10 fingers
and 10 toes.
A woman: He's running out of...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, like out of fingers and toes. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the purpose of, of God's system of increasing
the population.
For example, how come AIDS didn't show up
1,000 years ago?
There were homosexuals 1,000 years ago.
Why, why didn't AIDS show up then?
Can you guess?
Dr. Khalifa: Why do we have AIDS now and not 1,000 years
ago? Where did it come from?
A woman: They've become so vocal now and so violent
about it that they were once.
A woman: They've become (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: No.
A man: This is because of the Sheytan.
Audience: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Let's give Muhammad a chance to think.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Could you keep the children apart?
Dr. Khalifa: Call your child next to you.
A man: Makan.
Dr. Khalifa: Hany.
Dr. Khalifa: Hany. Hany. Come here. Come here.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: The only way to keep them quiet is to keep
them apart.
A man: Divide the room.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Hanan, come next to mom.
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. Where do you, where do you prefer to sit? In that chair over there?
Dr. Khalifa: You prefer to sit in that chair?
Hanan: No.
Dr. Khalifa: No?
Dr. Khalifa: Ok. You pick out a good spot.
What's the best spot?
Where you are?
Okay.
Okay, Muhammad.
Dr. Khalifa: Let's get the attention away from them.
A man: Like if they did it, the Romans, the Roman Empire, perhaps
mostly because of the (unintelligible).
A man: They have other diseases.
A man: (unintelligible) the population was small.
A man: Yes, it was very small.
(unintelligible)
A man: So, He give him just a test of what he tried
to make a perfect world with the Romans.
For instance, you take the Roman Empire
that the general idea, just like in the communists,
as long as it's on the paper, it's fantastic. It has to stay in the paper.
A man: And they tried to, they put it in application.
Dr. Khalifa: didn't work.
A man: The whole thing collapsed.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: And...
Dr. Khalifa: My feeling is that AIDS, ok, when, a thousand years
ago, the population of the earth was very small.
And Satan was able to handle that.
But now that the population increased, he's
losing control.
So, we get all these, all these starving children in Africa
and AIDS.
So, things are getting out of control for him.
And if I get the chance in the next few days,
maybe, we had examples here of Satan's incompetence,
where, where we, we have proved that his ability to see
is very limited.
I mean, God, I mean, God sees everything in the universe.
Not a single atom is out of God's control.
But we have very strong evidence that Satan's
control is very limited.
Dr. Khalifa: And he cannot, he had very serious limitations
with seeing.
Edip: By the way, you need to conclude the wrong (unintelligible). I think it's a wrong point.
Edip: Sheytan wants to, I think, prevent (unintelligible) starvation and, or AIDS.
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible)
Edip: To try to find a cure for AIDS or people, how do you say, charitable people, who try to, how do you say, help starving people.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: And do they, if I did it, do they help Satan to make it better?
Dr. Khalifa: He helps them. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan is trying very hard to make everything
perfect.
Edip: I know that, for example, if we have starving children, starving children,
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: we help Satan. By the way, we shouldn't help starving people.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, you help because that's your requirement. But it doesn't, it doesn't make any difference, as far as Satan is concerned.
Edip: Something he doesn't understand
Edip: if we try to have a good world, or have a
good, for example, faith, whatever.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Edip: If it, if to be good is Satan's object, ...
Dr. Khalifa: Your, your Zakat, your contribution is, is insignificant.
It will not cause, it will not counteract the damage that Satan is
doing by his incompetence, will not correct it.
But it is my duty and your duty to give Zakat,
and to be charitable.
And this is in Sura 36.
(36:47) أَنُطْعِمُ مَن لَّوْ يَشَآءُ ٱللَّهُ أَطْعَمَهُۥٓ
This is what the
unbelievers will say.
"You want me to feed somebody that God wants to starve? God wants him to starve, why should I feed him?"
Dr. Khalifa: This is what he's saying. But that's not...
Edip: I think in God's dominion, things will go bad... good, go to good, but in Satan's dominion, people
Edip: (unintelligible). Yes, go bad.
Dr. Khalifa: Things will go bad. Yes.
Edip: And Satan would want to make it good, good.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan is trying very hard to make it
good.
Dr. Khalifa: Let me, let me mention it now, and very quickly, anyway.
The miracle of Quran, which is a fantastic
finding at this time, came out, came out of Satan's pocket.
It was hidden in his pocket.
Because, because this is a long story.
I do not (unintelligible) to make it short, without doing
it injustice.
I was working for Monsanto company, and then I had to, I had to give a paper at the American Chemical Society meeting in Chicago, 1970.
And after I gave the paper, this gentleman approaches me, and he says he's the research director for Anheuser-Busch.
Same city where I was working. I was working for Monsanto in St. Louis.
Anheuser-Busch is the biggest brewery in the
world.
Because this is more alcohol than any place
in the world, drinks for example, beer.
And he came and he said "we would like you
to work for us."
So, I laughed.
I said "no way, I can't work for Anheuser-Busch."
He says "why?"
I said "because I'm a Muslim, and I can't
deal with alcohol."
He said "this position has nothing to do with
alcohol."
"You're gonna be in the food technology section, the food research section, and it has nothing to do with alcohol."
"It has to do with yeast, baker's yeast, and
brewer's yeast, and so on."
I said" I still, I still, I will be connected with the name of Anheuser-Busch, and this is something I don't want to be connected with, because of the name of Anheuser-Busch."
He said, then he started, started from another angle.
He said "what we're trying to do is, in the
world, there are millions of tons of yeast
"and other agricultural waste that we throw
away, and it's full of protein.
"If you can help us get, get this protein out and turn it into food, those starving people in your country and back in Africa will not be starving."
So, he's trying to do the humanitarian thing.
Dr. Khalifa: I mean, he was really, he was really persistent.
Dr. Khalifa: We must reverence God all the time.
I mean, people, people will be driving, and in a minute, they
get in an accident, and they're gone.
[17:68]  ... Or, that He will not send upon you a tempest, then you find no protector?
[17:69]  Have you guaranteed that He will not return you to the sea, then send upon you a storm that drowns you because of your disbelief without getting a second chance?
[17:70]  We have honored the children of Adam, and carried them on land and in the sea. We provided for them good provisions, and we honored them high above many of our creatures.
[17:71]  The day will come when we summon every people, together with their record. As for those who are given a record of righteousness, they will read their record and will not suffer the least injustice.
[17:72]  As for those who are blind in this life, they will be blind in the Hereafter; even a lot worse.
[17:73]  They almost diverted you from the commandments we revealed to you. They wanted you to fabricate something else, in order to consider you a friend.
[17:74]  If it were not that we strengthened you, you almost leaned towards them a little bit.
[17:75]  Had you done that, we would have doubled the retribution for you in this life, and after death, and you would have found no one to help you against us.
So, you can see the responsibility of, if you're in a position to be asked a question,
you have a great responsibility to give the
correct answer.
You cannot acquiesce to the people or play
into their wishes.
You have to give them the word of God, and without, without
any delusion or deviation because of this verse 75.
[17:75]  Had you done that, we would have doubled the retribution for you in this life, and after death, and you would have found no one to help you against us.
So, there's too much at stake.
So, if they want to talk you into lying some
white lies, say "absolutely not." Don't lie.
No white lies.
Dr. Khalifa: I'm gonna stop at this and open the
floor for questions.
A man: Satan is envious of us. You know...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, because some of us have hope to be redeemed
back to God's kingdom. Satan has no hope.
Dr. Khalifa: So, he's, he's envious. He wants to take as many of us as he can with him.
Edip: In verse 70, God praises children of Adam
and says,
[17:70]  ... and we honored them high above many of our creatures.
In other verses, we see God says that human
beings are stupid and they are wicked.
Edip: Here it says "honored them."
Dr. Khalifa: If you take a wicked person, he still can
ride a horse.
The horse is much better than the person,
but this is who, who is honored. This is, this is what this means.
And especially that it talks about carrying
people on the...
You see,
(17:70) حَمَلْنَـٰهُمْ فِى ٱلْبَرِّ وَٱلْبَحْرِ
We carry them, we provide them with rides.
And we, we honored them above many of our creatures.
You can see lions in the cage, but you don't
see a human being in a cage in the lion country.
If you go visit lion country, you will not find a human being in a cage and the lion is looking at the human, even though the lion is much stronger.
This is honoring the human being.
God gave us the minds, so we abuse them by setting traps for the animals and catching them, putting them in the zoo.
We ride the horse.
Use them as pets.
You can feed them anytime you want to.
Dr. Khalifa: Notice that we feed the cats, not the other
way around.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, they try. You can't blame them. Sometimes it works.
Edip: Rashad, the other point here, in Arabic,
(17:70) وَفَضَّلْنَـٰهُمْ عَلَىٰ كَثِيرٍۢ مِّمَّنْ خَلَقْنَا تَفْضِيلًۭا
Edip: This is men, they're not smart.
Edip: It means, above others is, men must include something
like human being or angels.
Dr. Khalifa: You can call the animals man, also.
Dr. Khalifa (Speaking Arabic): (unintelligible)
In this particular context, this particular structure,
grammatical structure, sometimes God says,
لِّلَّهِ مَن فِى ٱلسَّمَـٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضِ
And some say,
لِّلَّهِ مَا فِى ٱلسَّمَـٰوَٰتِ وَٱلْأَرْضِ
Of course.
Dr. Khalifa: Sometimes MAN (مَن) applies to inanimate
objects.
A man: Satan knew that he could not control, (unintelligible) he says "I will deceive them, but except for a few." He knew that.
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Not God's... The people who step into God's protection,
Satan cannot touch them.
A man: I mean, Satan (unintelligible) protection. Every day, the (unintelligible) pushed by Satan to try to make the wrong decisions.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, absolutely.
Dr. Khalifa: His main targets are the believers.
A man: But when you make a decision, say "Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem", still you can do something wrong.
Dr. Khalifa: He's waiting for you to make a mistake, to
step out.
He's waiting for you to step out, so he can
beat you up.
We step out by missing a prayer, for example.
Then, we're vulnerable.
And God puts precise limits on him, as far
as if you miss a Prayer, you're supposed to get in trouble.
Satan can only do so much, because of the limits.
Remember I said, if you, if you forget to say, "Bismillah" when you get up in the morning, when you forget to mention the name of God as the first thing you do in the morning, this will cost you $75.
To put, to put a dollar value
on it.
So in other words, God tells Satan "you can
only bother him to the amount of $75, but that's it.
Dr. Khalifa: So, if you don't have it, he'll give you
a small headache, a little annoyance.
A man: Or a flat tire.
Dr. Khalifa: Flat tire.
A man: No wonder that actually that the majority of the
people are against Islam.
Dr. Khalifa: Why?
A man: Well, it's obvious that because they don't like it. The law is too strict.
Dr. Khalifa: On the contrary.
A man: No, but in the eyes of the people, they perceive it as being...
Dr. Khalifa: (unintelligible). Yeah. Yes.
Actually, this is, this is a sign of the true religion.
It's, if you look at the, the different Christian sects
today, they acquiesce to the people's wishes.
What is, what is the book of the Seventh-day Adventists,
for example?
They must have their own specific rules.
Or the Christian scientists, or the Quakers,
or the Amish, or the Unitarians.
What is their book that they go by, a book of rules? Do they have a book of rules? The Catholics, what is the book of the Catholics?
Well, why why did they eat fish on Friday 20 years ago,
but not anymore?
Which book says "do not eat meat on Friday"?
And then now, it says "eat meat on Friday."
So, they acquiesce to the people's wishes. The objective is to get as many people in this church as possible.
Dr. Khalifa: That's a sign of a false, false religion, a false
doctrine.
A woman: (unintelligible) Church of Christ (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Church of Christ?
A woman: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Which one?
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khlaifa: No, but the Mormons also call themselves Church
of Christ.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And that's what they say.
A woman: Yeah, (unintelligible)
A woman: They think people (unintelligible)
A woman: And (unintelligible)
A woman: I think (unintelligible)
A woman: I mean, (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, don't be tricked. Yeah, this...
Dr. Khalifa: If you dig just a little bit beneath the surface,
you'll see them idolizing Jesus and Mary and the saints.
A woman: Yeah, (unintelligible). Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
A woman: But they don't (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Well, if they think Jesus is God or Son
of God, they already deviated from the Bible.
Dr. Khalifa: Because, well, do they say Jesus is God or Son of God?
A woman: Well, they say (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, the Trinity, right? That's not in the Bible.
A woman: Well, no, they don't believe in Trinity. (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: So, they say "he's the Father and the Son"?
A woman: Only the son (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Oh, (unintelligible) God the Father and Jesus the
Son.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, I mean, what do they believe in?
Dr. Khalifa: That's fine. They can do that as long as
God is the Father of all the righteous.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Father to (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You see, the name itself is, indicates idol worship.
It's not the Church of God.
If the Church of God, then we have to go a little deeper and see what
their (unintelligible).
But right from the title, it's the Church of Christ that
they have attached themselves to a human factor.
Dr. Khalifa: They are in trouble from the title.
A woman: Because one time they had, they had a program about
the (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. See, if the name is the Church of God, which is the name of one of the churches, then you have to move on to the next, next line.
But the first line says "the Church of Christ",
and that's, that's it.
They don't follow the Bible, because the Bible says that Jesus is not God and not the son of God, not the only son of God anyway.
And this is in all the Bibles of all denominations,
Catholic, Protestant, in John 20:17.
Where Jesus says "I'm ascending to my Father
and your Father, my God and your God.
Finished.
This kills the Trinity right there.
And this is consistent to the rest of the
text, I'm not just taking one verse.
Because in addition to this, the whole context
of the New Testament agrees with this.
And nowhere does it say "Jesus is God."
It doesn't say "I am God."
He may say "I'm the light and the life and
the first and the last and then and that, but never says "I'm God."
Why doesn't he?
Dr. Khalifa: Go ahead.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: I know.
Dr. Khalifa: It's true. Even, even if you take that, the things that he is.
"At the beginning there was the Word, the Word was with God, and the Word was God, this means Jesus is God", but it doesn't say that.
I mean, they just take you into a roundabout way, and then they come up with a conclusion that has nothing to do with the statement in the Bible.
The truth is, nowhere in the Bible does it
say "Jesus is God."
And three of the Gospels never say that Jesus
is the only begotten Son of God.
Only once in the Gospel of John does it say
that Jesus is the only begotten Son of God,
and that verse happens to be questionable
now by the, by the annual convention called "the Jesus Conference."
Please, get your children to be next to you,
separate them from each other.
Dr. Khalifa: Maha, come here, honey.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Hany, come here.
Dr. Khalifa: Maha.
Dr. Khalifa: Maha, come here.
Good girl.
Dr. Khalifa: Hmm, nice and quiet for 19 seconds.
A woman: Rashad
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A woman: How do you interpret then this word when he was
dying on the cross and he said to his God, to God "Father, Father, why have thou forsaken me?"
A woman: How do you...
Dr. Khalifa: No, he said "my God, my God."
Dr. Khalifa: They even put it in his language, "Eloi, Eloi", "Elí, Elí"
A woman: Didn't he say "Father, Father"?
Dr. Khalifa: No, he said "my God, my God, why have you
forsaken me?"
You probably read it "Father, Father", in some
other translation, but that's not...
Because they put it in Aramaic, in all the
Gospels. Elí, Elí, lemá sabachtháni?”
Which means "my God, my God, why have you
forsaken me?
It means he's not God, right?
For one thing.
The truth is, he never said that.
Dr. Khalifa: Just to compound the problem.
A man: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: We know now that he never said that. But if he said it according to them, it means he's not God.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there goes...
Feroz: He never said that because he had already died, right?
Dr. Khalifa: Because he was not there.
Feroz: Right.
Dr. Khalifa: His body was alive, but he was not there.
That was a body that did not respond to anything.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Edip: Yes, he didn't (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: No, no.
A man: But how come, how come that these people can believe
that he is God?
Dr. Khalifa: What's it next to daddy?
A man: How come that they can believe?
Dr. Khalifa: Who?
A man: That, that, that Jesus is actually God.
Dr. Khalifa: You're right. That's the...
A man: It's so contradictory.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly.
Dr. Khalifa: Well, see, Satan wants to point at us and say "look
how stupid they are."
I think Satan is hoping that so many humans
will out-Satan Satan, that God will, will have mercy on Satan.
Yes, quite a few people out-Satan Satan.
I can, I have a few examples.
In other words, Satan told them something
and they went too far in doing it.
Dr. Khalifa: So, Satan said "oh, oh, oh, I didn't tell you to do
all this."
A woman: But according to the Quran that I know what
you don't know.
Edip: For example, I can give you an example of this.
Dr. Khalifa: God said. Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Edip: I can give you an example.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, go ahead.
Edip: Satan doesn't deny God's existence.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: But communists, they go further.
Dr. Khalifa: Exactly. That's right.
Dr. Khalifa: Nai'ma.
Na'ima: Is there a way to know when (unintelligible)
Na'ima: Because I deal with anger sometimes. I'm gonna ...
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, if you have two things.
Na'ima: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: There are two things that come from Satan: fear and worry.
Na'ima: Fear and?
Dr. Khalifa: Fear and grief. Excuse me. Worry, worry or fear and grief.
Na'ima: What about anger?
Dr. Khalifa: Well, anger comes, but God says "the believers
suppress their anger."
So, anger happens, but you control it.
But remember throughout the Quran, you know
this very well, that God says, la khawfuna
(10:62) لَا خَوْفٌ عَلَيْهِمْ وَلَا هُمْ يَحْزَنُونَ
Dr. Khalifa: No fear, no grief. Two things.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, this is the suppress of, the believers suppress anger.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: So, anger happens, but you control it.
It's part of training our wild horse.
Anger is part of the wild horse that we are
training.
But really this is a very good criterion to remind us whether we are believers or not that we have fear, worry, or grief.
And God spreads this out in the Quran.
God says that fear is Satan's tool with which
he does it to his constituents.
This is why your insurance agents are probably
very close to Satan.
"What happens if you die tomorrow? What will happen to your family?"
Dr. Khalifa: Huh? Yes. Accidental death insurance.
A woman: (unintelligible), they rip them off.
Dr. Khalifa: Insurance is all based on fear.
A woman: I think that (unintelligible) has fear (unintelligible) Sheytan (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: You don't have fear.
A woman: You don't have fear.
Dr. Khalifa: Satan will try to put worry in your heart, but what I'm saying is that Satan is the source of these two things: worry and grief.
Edip: Rashad
Dr. Khalifa: When you grieve over anything, you're objecting
to God, what God did, that God is doing everything.
Edip: Rashad, the scare from cockroach is included?
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, absolutely.
Dr. Khalifa: Fear of cockroaches. Edip is definitely afraid of cockroaches.
Parivash: Cockroaches, so (unintelligible)
A man: If believer, I shouldn't be, I shouldn't go to a employee that
you shouldn't smoke.
Dr. Khalifa: I will avoid it. I'll avoid that.
A man: If I open a store, a variety of store, like
a 7-Eleven, like, I shouldn't sell any beer. It shouldn't be like that.
Dr. Khalifa: Right. I'll avoid it. Yes.
A man: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes?
A woman: Would phobias like (unintelligible)?
Dr. Khalifa: Yep.
Dr. Khalifa: Believers have no phobias.
The believers know that not a scratch will touch
you if you are in God's protection.
Not a scratch.
Dr. Khalifa: So, there'll be no phobia. You won't be afraid.
A man: We conquer these phobias.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: You conquer your phobias.
A man: But what if it is unconscious? (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, well, conscious or unconscious, your conscious being will convince your unconscious being
that there is no reason to be afraid since no scratch
will happen to you.
God puts in the strongest terms in the Quran
that there are guards around you. You are being guarded. In Arabic,
(82:10) وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكُمْ لَحَـٰفِظِينَ
These are two assurances.
Wa Inna (وَإِنَّ), La (لَ)
(82:10) وَإِنَّ عَلَيْكُمْ لَحَـٰفِظِينَ
You are guarded very well by God's guards.
Dr. Khalifa: So that they see to it that not a scratch
comes to you against God's will.
A woman: But (unintelligible).
Dr. Khalifa: Oh yeah, it's a long drawn process. It's a difficult... Not easy.
You see, once we, we apply for admission into
God's kingdom, there's a process that takes place.
Purification process, education.
As long as we do our homework, this is the textbook.
Dr. Khalifa: This is the manual.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: And tests.
A woman: familiar with the...
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah. That's right.
A woman: (unintelligible)
A man: I'm going to share with all of you, with your permission,
just an experience.
A man: Before we set the hour, and out of the boundary of, of God... A few months ago, I was, I was, you see, (unintelligible) I was driving.
There's a Sura, I really had difficult to understand. But when I put it in Arabic.
And English is different.
But when you listen to it enough,
and then suddenly, I started to understand
the word.
It's very easy because
the word in Arabic,
the Quranic word is "most corrupted."
A man: The understanding of the Arabs is corrupted.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So then, they have the barrier.
A man: And then, I think that's what happened (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Yes, well of course, there's God's law that
says "an insincere person cannot touch the Quran,
"cannot get one word out of it."
But the sincere searcher, even a disbeliever, or a Muslim, or a Jew, or a Christian, as long as the person is sincerely seeking the truth, it will be open to that person.
Otherwise, they cannot, they're blocked out.
They can be professors of Arabic language
at the Islamic University of Mecca.
And they cannot get one single letter out
of the Quran.
I have seen many people who have memorized
the Quran for many, many years. They never lost it.
But they didn't believe anything in it.
They didn't have access to the Quran.
All their understanding was wrong.
For example, all the Mullahs in Egypt, graduates
of Al-Azhar, they believe that Abraham's father in the Quran,
who was a disbeliever, is not
really his father, but his uncle.
This is what I mean by "they don't, they don't believe
anything in the Quran." There are many others.
This is because they built a theory that all
the lineage from Adam to Muhammad are believers.
So, if Muhammad is a descendant of Abraham,
his father could not be a disbeliever as we're told in the Quran.
So, one, one lie leads to another.
So, they refused to say, even though, as, as you know in the Quran, Abraham repeats, when he talks to his father, he keeps saying
"oh my father, oh my father, oh my father, oh my father, Ya Abati (يَـٰٓأَبَتِ), Ya Abati (يَـٰٓأَبَتِ)."
But God knew that they will do that.
Not once did he say "Ya Ammi (یا عمي)", you know.
Every time he said "Ya Abati (يَـٰٓأَبَتِ), Ya Abati (يَـٰٓأَبَتِ), Ya Abati (يَـٰٓأَبَتِ)."
Dr. Khalifa: He never said "oh my uncle", once.
A woman: (unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa: Right. According to this.
Dr. Khalifa: Yeah, sometimes you look at the English to
understand the Arabic word, you know,
because this Quranic Arabic, sometimes there
are words that are not used anymore in our
regular Tunisian Arabic or Egyptian Arabic.
So, if you go to the English, then we remember,
we know the meaning.
Dr. Khalifa: That's okay.
Edip: Rashad, a few days ago, we were reading Quran.
Edip: We had a question about prostrating.
Especially in Quran, I think there are some
different meanings.
Edip: We have...
Dr. Khalifa: Submission.
Edip: Submission, for example, God says,
Dr. Khalifa: Obedience.
Edip: Enter the city humbly,
(2:58) سُجَّدًا
Not prostrating. But Sujjadan (سُجَّدًا) means humbly.
Edip: Everything, creatures, they make Sujud, they prostrate God,
but in their way.
Dr. Khalifa: I never saw a tree go like this.
Edip: It means obey, obeying, obeying.
Dr. Khalifa: Submit
Edip: Yes, submission. And there is a word about, there's a verse about Joseph's parents and brothers, they fell prostrate for him.
It is, if you understand in this way that because only God,
we should prostrate only to God. How can we understand this?
It was a question.
Edip: How did they fell prostrate for Joseph?
Dr. Khalifa: Well,...
Edip: Like this way? Like this way?
Dr. Khalifa: No, Behrouz was worried about his brother.
And then, he called him by phone, and his brother
answered the phone, and everything was alright.
So, as soon as he finished, he fell prostrate.
Dr. Khalifa: He was really prostrating to God.
Edip: Ok.
Dr. Khalifa: So, the same...
Edip: I gave him the answer, but I was not sure.
Dr. Khalifa: When they met Joseph, they were so thankful
to God that they fell prostrate.
They did not feel prostrate to Joseph. They
fell prostrate before God, thanking him because
Dr. Khalifa: they are united with Joseph.
Edip: But the English translation, I think there
must be a correction.
Edip: "Before Joseph", instead of "for Joseph." If this
is "for Joseph", it's ok. This is my understanding.
Dr. Khalifa: This is what the Arabic said. But your understanding must be that they fell prostrate, thanking God.
He didn't fall prostrate for, for his brother.
He was prostrating to God and thanking God
that everything is ok. But the Arabic says,
(12:100) وَخَرُّوا۟ لَهُۥ سُجَّدًۭا
Edip:
وَخَرُّوا۟ لَهُۥ
(unintelligible)
Dr. Khalifa:
سُجَّدًا لله
Dr. Khalifa: Same, same expression.
Edip: Also, Rashad,...
Dr. Khalifa: So, but I'm, I'm translating the Arabic exactly the
way.
And if God wants some people to be confused
about it, that's their problem,
but you and I will understand that prostration
is only for God, not for humans.
Dr. Khalifa: There's a, there are some traps in the Quran for the
unbelievers.
Edip: And I think that this is a fulfillment of the dream.
Dr. Khalifa: Right.
Edip: In dream, sun, and all planets, no, no, all planets, they
are prostrating to sun.
Dr. Khalifa: No, no, no.
Edip: Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: The sun, the moon, and eleven planets
Edip: prostrating
Dr. Khalifa: to Joseph.
Edip: Joseph now, I think, represents sun because
all these planets, they turn around the sun. They...
Dr. Khalifa: No, the sun represents the father, the moon represents
the mother, and the eleven planets are his eleven brothers.
Dr. Khalifa: They were all prostrating to Joseph.
Edip: Oh, oh, yes.
Dr. Khalifa: This is, in fact, this is in the books of
dream interpretations in the Arab world.
Dr. Khalifa: The sun means the father and the moon means
the mother, and so on. And they take it from this.
A man: But in the next verse, he says,...
Edip: (unintelligible) Yes.
Dr. Khalifa: Pardon?
Edip: Maybe earth.
Dr. Khalifa: No, maybe nothing, he's just Joseph. Just in the dream.
Dr. Khalifa: A dream can have many representations. What is seven fat cows eating seven skinny cows? Or vice versa.
A man: So, he's telling him "don't tell your brothers."
[12:5]  ... Surely, the devil is man's worst enemy.
Dr. Khalifa: Yes.
A man: So, we see...
Dr. Khalifa: Because the devil will stir up his brothers
against him. The devil drives wedges among the brothers.
Dr. Khalifa: Okay. Next time we'll meet at seven o'clock, IN SHAA ALLAH.
A man: IN SHAA ALLAH.
Dr. Khalifa: For the Night Prayer. Salat Al-Isha.
If you miss, if you miss the Night
Prayer, we meet at six o'clock in the morning for the Fajr Prayer.
Dr. Khalifa: 286.
A woman: 296 or 86?
A man: 86.
Dr. Khalifa: 286.
Dr. Khalifa: Thank you, Muhammad. We're waiting for you.
IN SHAA ALLAH.
أعوذ بِٱللَّهِ مِنَ ٱلشَّيْطَـٰنِ ٱلرَّجِيمِ
Bism Allah Arrahman Arraheem
Quran Is Wisdom
Just the subtitle provokes a short discussion
here because
people who are trying very hard to
go to Hell, people are storming the gates of Hell and...